<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vassilis Sioros | Software / Machine Learning Engineer</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Vassilis Sioros | Software / Machine Learning Engineer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://billsioros.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploratory Data Analysis</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/exploratory-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/exploratory-data-analysis/</guid><description>Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) is like being a detective at a party full of numbers. Let&amp;rsquo;s take the Heart Disease Prediction Dataset as an example.
Imagine you walk into this party, and instead of guests, there are columns of data: ages, blood pressures, cholesterol levels, and so on. Your job as the detective is to mingle with these numbers, get to know them, and uncover their secrets.
You start by looking around to see who&amp;rsquo;s who.</description></item><item><title>Heart Disease Prediction</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/heart-disease-prediction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/heart-disease-prediction/</guid><description>In a previous post, we conducted Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) of the Heart Disease Prediction Dataset and created a processed version of the dataset.
Cardiovascular diseases (CVDs) are like the ultimate party crashers, claiming the lives of 17.9 million people every year—that’s a whopping 31% of all deaths worldwide! Most of these are due to heart attacks and strokes, and what’s even scarier is that many victims are under 70. But what if we could see these crashers coming from a mile away?</description></item><item><title>Let's Talk Python Metaclasses</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/python-metaclasses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/python-metaclasses/</guid><description>Python metaclasses give you control over class creation and behavior. They act as blueprints, shaping inheritance and behavior. Just as classes govern instances, metaclasses oversee classes.
A little know gem Ever heard of a metaclass called abc.ABC? Chances are you&amp;rsquo;ve been using it without even realizing it. This little gem is pretty handy for crafting abstract base classes (ABCs) in Python. It&amp;rsquo;s like the rulebook that says, &amp;ldquo;Hey, if you&amp;rsquo;re a subclass, you gotta follow these rules and implement these methods.</description></item></channel></rss>