<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vassilis Sioros | Software / Machine Learning Engineer</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Vassilis Sioros | Software / Machine Learning Engineer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://billsioros.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a REST API</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/heart-disease-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/heart-disease-rest-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Heart disease is like the uninvited guest that crashes the party, causing 17.9 million deaths every year—about 31% of all deaths worldwide, with many victims under 70. But what if we could predict when this party crasher is coming? That’s where machine learning steps in, superhero-style! These models act like crystal balls for your health, scanning data for warning signs like high blood pressure or cholesterol to predict who’s at risk of heart disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart Disease Prediction</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/heart-disease-prediction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/heart-disease-prediction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cardiovascular diseases (CVDs) are like the ultimate party crashers, claiming the lives of 17.9 million people every year—that’s a whopping 31% of all deaths worldwide! Most of these are due to heart attacks and strokes, and what’s even scarier is that many victims are under 70. But what if we could see these crashers coming from a mile away? Enter machine learning: the superhero of the data world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Machine learning models can dig through mountains of data to spot patterns and predict who might be at risk of heart disease. Think of them as your health fortune-tellers, using factors like high blood pressure, diabetes, and cholesterol levels to give you an early heads-up. With these models in action, we can catch potential heart problems before they turn into full-blown emergencies, helping to save lives and keep hearts happy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploratory Data Analysis</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/exploratory-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/exploratory-data-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) is like being a detective at a party full of numbers. Let&amp;rsquo;s take the &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/fedesoriano/heart-failure-prediction">Heart Disease Prediction Dataset&lt;/a> as an example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imagine you walk into this party, and instead of guests, there are columns of data: ages, blood pressures, cholesterol levels, and so on. Your job as the detective is to mingle with these numbers, get to know them, and uncover their secrets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You start by looking around to see who&amp;rsquo;s who. You might notice that the average age of the guests is around 50. Maybe you spot some interesting patterns, like how those with high cholesterol tend to hang out in one corner. You create some cool charts and graphs, which are like taking snapshots of the party. These visuals help you see at a glance who the outliers are—the really tall guy in the middle of a crowd of short folks, or the person who&amp;rsquo;s overdressed for the occasion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let's Talk Python Metaclasses</title><link>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/python-metaclasses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://billsioros.github.io/posts/python-metaclasses/</guid><description>&lt;p>Python metaclasses give you control over class creation and behavior. They act as blueprints, shaping inheritance and behavior. Just as classes govern instances, metaclasses oversee classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-little-know-gem">A little know gem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ever heard of a metaclass called &lt;code>abc.ABC&lt;/code>? Chances are you&amp;rsquo;ve been using it without even realizing it. This little gem is pretty handy for crafting abstract base classes (ABCs) in Python. It&amp;rsquo;s like the rulebook that says, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Hey, if you&amp;rsquo;re a subclass, you gotta follow these rules and implement these methods.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>